Garrison Family Papers, 1694-2005 (bulk 1830-1950)
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES X. STEPHENSON FAMILY (1818-1973)
  - Correspondence
    - Stephenson
      - Benjamin Turner (1849)
        - Garrison, Edith Stephenson and WLG (1874) 1888-1906 (Box 274, Folder 18)
        - Stephenson, Luda Grant 1869 (Box 274, Folder 19)
      - Benjamin Turner (1886) 1898-24, undated (Box 274, Folder 20)
      - Blanche 1924-28, undated (Box 274, Folder 21)
      - Charles F. 1862-65 (Box 274, Folder 22)
      - Elizabeth Flagg 1911 (Box 274, Folder 23)
      - Ethel Grant 1914 (Box 274, Folder 24)
      - Florence Reynoldsundated (Box 274, Folder 25)
      - Harriet 1884-1911 (Box 275, Folder 1)
      - Harris Grant
        - Garrison, Edith Stephenson and WLG (1874) 1892-57, undated (Box 275, Folder 2-5)
        - Stephenson, Barton 1940 (Box 275, Folder 6)
      - Harris M.undated (Box 275, Folder 7)
      - John Bryant 1866-75, undated (Box 275, Folder 8)
      - Luda Grant
        - Garrison, David Lloydundated (Box 275, Folder 9)
        - Garrison, Edith Stephenson and WLG (1874) 1886-1920, undated (Box 275, Folder 10-12)
        - Stephenson, Benjamin Turner (1849) 1869-71 (Box 275, Folder 13-16)
      - Madge Lovell
        - Garrison, Edith Stephenson and WLG (1874) 1908-48, undated (Box 276, Folder 1)
        - Stephenson, Lucinda ("Luda") Grantundated (Box 276, Folder 2)
      - Nancy K. Hall 1880-1902 (Box 276, Folder 3)
      - Walter
        - Outgoing
          - Garrison, David Lloyd
            - 1918-49, undated (Box 276, Folder 4)
            - Scrapbook: "File of letters together with enclosures, clippings of writings of Lucien Price and some others" 1927-29 (Box 276, Folder 5-6)
          - Garrison, Edith Stephenson Garrison and William Lloyd Garrison (1874) 1915-43, undated (Box 276, Folder 7-9)
          - "Kids" 1926 (Box 276, Folder 10)
          - Stephenson, Arthur 1921 (Box 276, Folder 11)
        - Incoming 1919-24 (Box 276, Folder 12)
    - Warner, Caroline Holt 1942-50, undated (Box 277, Folder 1)
    - Willis
      - Benjamin 1953 (Box 277, Folder 2)
      - Luda Marguerite ("Margo") and Frank 1900-64, undated (Box 277, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified 1872-1944, undated (Box 277, Folder 4)
- SERIES XI. SCRAPBOOKS 1833-1908
  - Garrison
    - Agnes
      - circa 1870s-85 (Box 278)
      - "The travels of A.G." 1900-01 (Box 278)
    - George Thompson
      - 1840s-1901 (Box 279)
      - circa 1833-1900 (Box 280)
      - circa 1885-1901 (Box 281)
      - Record of the 55th Massachusetts Infantry 1868 (Box 281)
    - William Lloyd (1838)
      - circa Oct 1856-Sept 1859 (1838) (Box 282)
      - circa Jan 1860-Oct 1862 (Box 282)
      - Dec 1860-Sep 1862 (1838) (Box 283)
      - circa Aug 1861-Aug 1862 (1838) (Box 284)
      - circa Aug 1861-Apr 1862 (Box 284)
      - "Business Ventures"1883-97 (1838) (Box 285)
      - circa Jan-Jul 1899 (1838) (Box 286)
      - "Football, Fraternities" 1891-1907 (Box 286)
      - "Anti imperialism," 1899-1901 (1838) (Box 287)
      - "Negro, suffrage," 1898-1902 (1838) (Box 288)
      - 1903-06 (1838) (Box 289)
      - 1907-08 (1838) (Box 290)
- SERIES XII. ARTIFACTS 1833-1914
  - Engraved silver cup presented to WLG (1805) and signed by abolitionists1833 (Box 291)
  - Statuettes by John Rogers of Elizabeth Fry and William Wilberforce (Box 292)
  - Medals and ribbons 1895-1914, undated (Box 293)
  - Harriet Martineau's dinner bell (Box 294)
  - Two black top hats (belonging to ?) and an embroidered scull cap (WLG 1838) (Box 295)
  - Wallet embossed "William L. Garrison" (Box 295)
  - Oil painting of William Lloyd Garrison (1874) as boy (Box 296)
  - Oil painted sign: "Pagan Point W.L.G." (Box 297)
  - Black topcoat and waistcoat belonging to WLG (1838) (Box 298)
  - Oil portrait of WLG (1805) by M.G. Torrey (Box 299)
  - Suffrage banner: black felt with gold lettering "Newton", carried in suffrage parade, belonged to Edith Stephenson Garrison (Box 299)
  - Silk antislavery banner, painted by Josiah Wolcottcirca 1840s, probably made to be sold to raise money at antislavery fairs. Framed and hanging on the wall in the Sophia Smith Collection reading room (Box 299)
  - Statue: The Fugitive's Story by John Rogers (John C. Whittier, Henry Ward Beecher, and WLG (1805) ) done on 12 x18 base. (Sophia Smith Collection reading room) (Box 299)
  - Statue of WLG (1805) by Anne Whitney (plaster, 27 1/2 inches) (Smith College Museum of Art) (Box 299)
  - Clock: Presented to WLG (1805) April 5, 1867 from "a few friends among his colored fellow citizens.." (owned by the Smith College Museum of Art) (Box 299)
  - Ivory handled cane (40th wedding anniversary) with silver band engraved: "W.L.G. 1864-1904 E.W.G. (Box 299)
- Indexes
  - Notes on Garrison letters (Frank Wright Garrison) (Box 300, Folder 1)
  - Brown, Anna Temple Coffin 1858-1900 (Box 300, Folder 2)
  - Cavendar 1874, undated (Box 300, Folder 3)
  - Clark Family 1890-1957 (Box 300, Folder 4)
  - Davis
    - Anna Coffin 1851-89 (Box 300, Folder 5)
    - Maria Mott 1875-87 (Box 300, Folder 6)
  - Garrison
    - Agnes 1874-1928 (Box 300, Folder 7-10)
    - Charles 1882-1929 (Box 300, Folder 11)
    - Ellen Wright
      - 1851-99 (Box 300, Folder 12-16)
      - 1900-30 (Box 301, Folder 1-3)
    - Frank Wright 1888-1949 (Box 301, Folder 4)
    - Helen Benson 1866-71 (Box 301, Folder 5)
    - Lucy McKim 1852-76 (Box 301, Folder 6)
    - Mildred Yarnall 1906 (Box 301, Folder 7)
    - William Lloyd (1805) 1839-78 (Box 301, Folder 8)
    - William Lloyd (1838)
      - 1867-1908 (Box 301, Folder 9)
      - To Ellen Wright Garrison 1864-1910 (Box 301, Folder 10)
    - William Lloyd (1874) 1891-1948 (Box 301, Folder 11)
  - Lord, Maria Mott 1853-1900 (Box 301, Folder 12)
  - Mott
    - Marianna Pelham 1844-71 (Box 301, Folder 13)
    - Lucretia Coffin 1851-75 (Box 301, Folder 14)
    - Thomas 1872 (Box 301, Folder 15)
  - Norton, Katharine Garrison 1881-1906 (Box 301, Folder 16)
  - Osborne, Eliza Wright 1884-97 (Box 301, Folder 17)
  - Stanton, Elizabeth Cady 1856-74 (Box 301, Folder 18)
  - Wright
    - David 1872-74 (Box 301, Folder 19)
    - Martha Coffin
      - Ellen Wright Garrison 1847-74 (Box 301, Folder 20)
      - Lucretia Coffin Mott 1842-68 (Box 301, Folder 21)
      - Maria Pelham Mott 1836-65 (Box 301, Folder 22)
      - Eliza Wright Osborne 1850-74 (Box 301, Folder 23)
      - Peter Pelham 1825 (Box 301, Folder 24)
      - David Wright 1832-74 (Box 302, Folder 1)
      - Tallman Wright 1846-53 (Box 302, Folder 2)
      - William Pelham Wright 1854-61 (Box 302, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous 1841-77 (Box 302, Folder 4)
    - Tallman 1848-54 (Box 302, Folder 5)
    - William Pelham 1875-89 (Box 302, Folder 6)
  - California Trip 1903 (Box 302, Folder 7)
  - Condolences for WLG (1838)1909 (Box 302, Folder 8)
  - Letters to the Garrisons and Wrights 1821-1956 (Box 302, Folder 9)
- TRANSCRIPTIONS AND NOTES
  - Primarily Mott and Wright correspondence-duplicates are filed with original letters (Box 303-304)
- RESTRICTED MATERIALS
  - RESTRICTED Fragile original correspondence-USE photocopies filed in boxes 5-272 (Box 305-309)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS
    - WLG (1805): "1835-1885. William Lloyd Garrison - A poem written by Elijah W. Smith.... in commemoration of the 50th anniversary of the mobbing of WLG, 1835" (Box 302A)
    - John Brown: "Address of John Brown to the Virginia court about to receive sentence of death" 1859 (Box 302A)
    - Harriet Winslow Sewall: "Lucretia Mott and Lydia Maria Child" 1880 (Box 302A)
  - SERIES III. CORRESPONDENCE
    - Hannah Parrish to David Lloyd Garrison
      - Letter 1933 (Box 302A)
      - Cartoon drawing 1933 (Box 302A)
  - SERIES V. FINANCIAL MATERIALS
    - William Lloyd Garrison (1874): Insurance certificates 1900-53 (Box 302A)
  - SERIES VI. SUBJECT FILES
    - Abolition
      - American Anti-slavery Society
        - The EmancipatorJanuary 2, 1839 (Box 302A)
      - Correspondence - George Thompson to Mrs. Smeal 1835 (Box 302A)
      - The Liberator, 1 Jan 1831 issue and subscription letter 1839 (Box 302A)
      - Fugitive Slave Law - "No Higher Law" (Box 302A)
      - National Anti-Slavery Society, Declaration of Sentiments of the Anti-slavery Convention, PhiladelphiaDecember 4, 1833 (Box 302A)
      - Pennsylvania Anti-slavery Society, The Pennsylvania FreemanMarch 25, 1847 (Box 302A)
    - Periodicals
      - Boston Patriot 1810 (Box 302A)
      - The Free Press 1826 (Box 302A)
      - Hope and Home 1894-96 (Box 302A)
      - The Star4 May 1901 (Box 302A)
      - The Woman's Journal26 Jan 1907 (Box 302A)
    - Suffrage
      - Organizations: Massachusetts Woman Suffrage Association, victory parade 1915 (Box 302A)
      - National Citizen 1880 (Box 302A)
    - Temperance: National Philanthropist 1828 (Box 302A)
  - SERIES VIII. MEMORABILIA
    - Agnes Garrison: Passports 1902, 1914 (Box 302B)
    - Ellen Wright Garrison
      - Passport 1914 (Box 302B)
      - Marriage certificate with list of guests 1864 (Box 302B)
    - Edith Stephenson Garrison: Poster for the Hampton Singers 1936 (Box 302B)
    - Eleanor Garrison: Radcliffe diploma 1906 (Box 302B)
    - William Lloyd Garrison (1805): Rockledge deed, Hunnewell to Walley and hill1854 (Box 302B)
    - David Lloyd Garrison
      - Salute from the Lincoln Planning Board 1968 (Box 302B)
      - Marriage certificate with guest list 1945 (Box 302B)
      - Pagan Bray country club drawingsundated (Box 302B)
      - Art (paintings and drawings)undated (Box 302B)
    - William Lloyd Garrison (1874)
      - Harvard University diploma 1896 (Box 302B)
      - Harvard University Sound Money Campaign 1896 (Box 302B)
      - Harvard class of 1897 poster (Box 302B)
      - Wedding guests 1901 (Box 302B)
    - William Lloyd Garrison (1902): Country Day School diploma1920 (Box 302B)
  - SERIES IV. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES
    - William Lloyd Garrison (1805): The Philadelphia InquirerOctober 28, 1861 (Map-case Flat File)
    - Lucy McKim Garrison: Slave songs of the US: Enid's Song; Songs of the Freeman of Port Royal: collected and arranged by Lucy McKim Garrison; 1862, unidentified. (Map-case Flat File)
  - SERIES VI. SUBJECT FILES
    - Abolition: The EmancipatorJanuary 2, 1839 (Map-case Flat File)
    - American Anti-Slavery Society: Broadside 1835 [?] (Map-case Flat File)
    - Periodicals
      - Boston Weekly Transcript 1879 (Map-case Flat File)
      - Daily Evening Transcript 1850 (Map-case Flat File)
      - New York Evangelist 1850 (Map-case Flat File)
    - Race
      - The Freeman 1895 (Map-case Flat File)
      - The Guardian 1906 (Map-case Flat File)
      - The Exodus 1800, 1881 (Map-case Flat File)
    - Wianno: Drawings and blueprints (Map-case Flat File)
  - SERIES VII. PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Sumner, Charles and Longfellowundated (Map-case Flat File)
    - Garrison, William Lloyd (1805) and sonscirca 1870s (Map-case Flat File)
    - Garrison, William Lloyd (1874) with classmatescirca late 1880s (Map-case Flat File)
    - Garrison, David Lloyd, at Country Day and Deane Schools 1924-30 (Map-case Flat File)
  - SERIES VIII. MEMORABILIA
    - John Bright Garrison: Harvard University, Hasty Pudding Theatre poster 1930 (Map-case Flat File)
  - SERIES X. STEPHENSON FAMILY
    - Genealogical chart (Map-case Flat File)
    - Briant P. Stephenson land grant 1855 (Map-case Flat File)
  - SERIES XII. ARTIFACTS
    - Ivory handled cane (40th wedding anniversary) with silver band engraved: "W.L.G. 1864-1904 E.W.G. (Map-case Flat File)
- BOOKS ON SHELF
  - Child, Lydia Maria, Isaac T. Hopper: A True Life 1853
  - Garrison, Wendell P., Sonnets and Lyrics for the Ever-Womanly 1898
  - Garrison, Wendell P., William Lloyd Garrison, 1805-1879; The story of his life told by his children1885-1889. 4v (2 copies of v. 1)
  - Locke, David Ross. "Swingin Round The Cirkle" by Petroleum V. Nasby (pseud) His ideas of men, Politics, and things, as set forth in his letters to the public press, during the year 1866. Illustrated by Thomas Nast, 1867
  - Kemble, Frances Anne. Journal Of A Residence On A Georgian Plantation in 1838-18391863
  - May, Samuel Joseph. Some Recollections of Our Antislavery Conflict 1869
  - Why Wars Must Cease, by Carrie Chapman Catt, Mrs. Franklin D. Roosevelt, Jane Addams, Judge Florence E. Allen, Mrs. Wm. Brown,Meloney, Dr. Alice Hamilton, Mary E. Woolley, Florence Brewer Boeckel, Emily Newell Blair [and] Dorothy Canfield Fisher; Rose Young, editor 1935.